<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/wellpro-blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/wellpro-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-25T06:19:54+00:00</updated><id>/wellpro-blog/</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">6 powerful steps to fuel your Ambition</title><link href="/wellpro-blog/lifestyle/2017/02/25/6-powerful-steps-to-fuel-your-ambition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 powerful steps to fuel your Ambition" /><published>2017-02-25T10:14:20+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-25T10:14:20+00:00</updated><id>/wellpro-blog/lifestyle/2017/02/25/6-powerful-steps-to-fuel-your-ambition</id><content type="html" xml:base="/wellpro-blog/lifestyle/2017/02/25/6-powerful-steps-to-fuel-your-ambition.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-connect-to-your-inner-why&quot;&gt;1. Connect to your inner ‘why’.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(116, 116, 116); font-weight: 400; font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;Connecting to your why, will help you to think more clearly, empower your relationships, broaden your windows of opportunity and most importantly it will fuel your energy and ambition. Your why is the reason you wake up every morning and do what you do day after day. When you truly connect to your inner why, you will never be the same again. Connecting to your why can sometimes happen through a process called journaling. Journaling is a type of writing where you just start writing all of your thoughts out on a paper at night before you go to bed. It continues on until your mind starts to see certain patterns and begins to have some clarity on what really matters most to you and what brings you down and further from yourself. Connecting to your why can also happen through inspiration when meditating. Some people connect to their why, via a life coach, who has professional techniques and processes designed to connect your to your life purpose or why&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(116, 116, 116); font-size: 16px; font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-establish-healthy-habits&quot;&gt;2. Establish healthy habits. &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After we connect to our why, we feel inspired and it is a perfect time to start or improve your health and fitness routine. A regular health and fitness program, will prepare our body and mind for action towards your ambitions. We all want to feel our best. Don’t allow your sense of purpose and ambition to over-ride your requirement for physical health and fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get adequate sleep. Sleep allows the body to operate at peak performance by deactivating harmful chemicals which are produced in the body during stress and little sleep. These chemicals damage your nervous system as well as your hormonal system and indicate that you are working at a sub level fuel for your ambition. Add to your diet lots of pure water which will rejuvenate your cells and improve blood levels and blood pressure when you are over challenged. Eat whole foods and remove all processed and heavily fried foods. This will help your body to lose weight, feel lighter and increase your sense of resolve for the day. Stop bad habits such as smoking which will further decrease your life expectancy and your resolve for a quality life.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Stephanie Niazi</name></author><summary type="html">1. Connect to your inner ‘why’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Testing blog</title><link href="/wellpro-blog/mindfulness/2017/02/24/testing-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testing blog" /><published>2017-02-24T22:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-24T22:15:00+00:00</updated><id>/wellpro-blog/mindfulness/2017/02/24/testing-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="/wellpro-blog/mindfulness/2017/02/24/testing-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;Testing blog&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Testing blog</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/wellpro-blog/uploads/2017/02/23/pexels-photo-315658-2.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring Fear with Compassion</title><link href="/wellpro-blog/happiness/2017/02/23/exploring-fear-with-compassion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Fear with Compassion " /><published>2017-02-23T19:14:26+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-23T19:14:26+00:00</updated><id>/wellpro-blog/happiness/2017/02/23/exploring-fear-with-compassion</id><content type="html" xml:base="/wellpro-blog/happiness/2017/02/23/exploring-fear-with-compassion.html">&lt;p&gt;When we experience fear, sometimes the last thing we feel we want to do is meet it head on. Our habitual response may be to distract ourselves, or try to ignore it. However, by doing this, we miss out on the opportunities for freedom and growth that fear offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we can investigate our fear with compassion and openness, we can move through it and beyond, to a more spacious place – not a place where the fear ceases to exist, but where it can safely co-exist with other aspects of our humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her talk ‘Transforming Two Fears: FOF and FOMO’, Tara Brach explains two common types of fear: fear of failure (FOF) and fear of missing out (FOMO), and what we can do to meet these fears with kind awareness, curiosity and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fear-of-failure&quot;&gt;Fear of Failure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can encompass many different fears, not just the obvious ones that may come to mind. Fear of failing in our career, education or relationships is common, and something we all share. So is the fear of not being able to cope with certain situations, for example ‘How would I cope if I became unwell?’ There are probably countless other situations that we may have imagined, and consequently worried about, namely about our ability to successfully meet those challenges. Fear of rejection, or of not being good enough also fit this category. Tara describes it as ‘fear of deficiency’; a feeling that we’re simply not prepared or equipped for what the future may bring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These fears keep us alert to everything that might go wrong, in either our immediate or distant futures. They come from the primal part of our brain, which simply wants to avoid harm. It’s tempting to believe that by analysing everything that could go wrong, we will be more prepared. And sometimes this may be true. But usually what happens is that we become disconnected from the present moment, which is where our resiliency and strength truly exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fear-of-missing-out&quot;&gt;Fear of Missing Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fear of missing out is somewhat different. It’s that nagging fear that we’re missing out on pleasure or gratification of some kind, that our lives could or should be different somehow, that we could have more, that things could be better. This fear creates a feeling of dissatisfaction with our lives. Or it can create a fearful sense of urgency, that we ‘must’ take this particular action now, otherwise we might miss out on an opportunity forever. Advertisers regularly take advantage of this shared fear of ours, promoting limited time offers, and encouraging material competitiveness with our peers, for example. But we may also experience this fear in relation to things such as finding love, having children, or losing our youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;investigating-fear-through-meditation&quot;&gt;Investigating Fear Through Meditation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tara Brach offers two reflective meditations to help us meet these two distinct fears, with honesty, acceptance and kindness. After all, these are fears that we all experience. Although we often believe they are a personal failing on our part, they are in fact a shared experience across all of humanity, and even other species too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflecting-on-the-fear-of-failure&quot;&gt;Reflecting on the Fear of Failure &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The first step of widening your identity – not being caught in the cocoon of fear – is to just investigate. Just to notice it, witness it,” says Tara. “So you might bear witness, without judgement, and just ask yourself, ‘So where do I become afraid of falling short?’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a sense of openness and curiosity, we can explore the kinds of thoughts and memories that come to mind when we reflect on our fears of failure, rejection or not being enough. Can we think of one particular habitual fear that comes to us time and time again? Rather than trying to dance around it and avoid it, take some time to really meet it within yourself. Notice the reactions it triggers, the typical line of defence you take against it. And rather than seeing it as your personal fear, Tara suggests viewing it as ‘the’ fear – one of the archetypal fears that all humans experience. How does doing this with a sense of kindness affect that fear?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reflecting-on-the-fear-of-missing-out&quot;&gt;Reflecting on the Fear of Missing Out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with the same openness, we can feel into the distinctly different fear of missing out; the stress or anxiety we experience from feeling there is something pleasurable or gratifying to be had that we don’t yet have. What feels particularly important to us to have right now? The range of experiences this could include is vast, from not wanting to miss out on the latest piece of technology, to not wanting to miss out on achieving an enlightening insight. It could be that we’re frightened of never achieving the level of wealth or success that we crave, or of not finding ‘the one’. The less we feel that our needs are being met in that area of life, the more intense our fear of missing out on that thing will be. Our desire or fixation on what we don’t yet have can cut us off from the present moment. By exploring our FOMO, we may notice that shift, from a mindful state to a more narrowed, restricted view. But again, this is not a personal fear of our own creation, it is ‘the’ fear of missing out, arising in us as it arises in all of us. How does it feel in the mind, heart and body? Tara reminds us that, “You’re bearing witness to how this human self is when caught in this conditioning. So bring some kindness to it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-fear-as-a-portal&quot;&gt;Using Fear as a Portal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If we deepen our attention when we’re caught in the fear of failure, when we’re caught in that fear of rejection… the more we discover a kind of timeless belonging that takes us beyond that fear. And with FOMO, the more we get in touch with that fear of missing out and that wanting for gratification, the more we discover that what we wanted was always here. And we tap into an absolute infinite flow of creativity, of dynamism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So by meeting these fears with attention and compassion, we can use them as portals to move beyond, into greater spaciousness. Our fears will still be there, and will still catch us. Yet by mindfully greeting them each time we notice them arise, we can become less and less contained by them. We can stop basing so much of our identity around constantly trying to subdue these fears by using outside sources, such as money or achievements, and instead tap into something deeper within.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>stephanie-niazi</name></author><summary type="html">When we experience fear, sometimes the last thing we feel we want to do is meet it head on. Our habitual response may be to distract ourselves, or try to ignore it. However, by doing this, we miss out on the opportunities for freedom and growth that fear offers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/wellpro-blog/uploads/2017/02/23/pexels-photo-315658-4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Test post</title><link href="/wellpro-blog/wellness/2017/02/23/test-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test post" /><published>2017-02-23T17:33:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-23T17:33:00+00:00</updated><id>/wellpro-blog/wellness/2017/02/23/test-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/wellpro-blog/wellness/2017/02/23/test-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Test post&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Test post</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/wellpro-blog/img/main_slide_1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Weaving Mindfulness into your Day</title><link href="/wellpro-blog/mindfulness/2015/11/12/just-a-thought-weaving-mindfulness-into-your-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weaving Mindfulness into your Day " /><published>2015-11-12T19:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-12T19:09:00+00:00</updated><id>/wellpro-blog/mindfulness/2015/11/12/just-a-thought-weaving-mindfulness-into-your-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="/wellpro-blog/mindfulness/2015/11/12/just-a-thought-weaving-mindfulness-into-your-day.html">&lt;p&gt;People often complain that they don’t have the time to practise mindfulness. If your one of those busy ones, you might like this: Think about three things you do each day. Like brushing your teeth, being in nature and having lunch. Then link this activity to a mindfulness practice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature + Mindfulness: Every time you go for a walk become fully present for a couple of moments. Connect with all your senses: smell the air, feel the wind on your skin and just walk. When you notice your mind going into thinking, just gently return to the present moment experience of simply being in nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lunch + Gratitude: Before or during each meal spend 20 seconds consciously feeling grateful for having food on your plate. Bring to mind where the food comes from and how lucky you are to live in a country where there is enough food. Stay with the feeling of gratitude and notice how it makes you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brushing your teeth + Something Good: In the evening when you brush your teeth, make a habit of bringing to mind one good think that happened on that day. Maybe you had a wonderful conversation with a friend or someone gave you a gift. Whatever it is, close your eyes, bring the situation to mind and stay with that mental image for some time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Stephanie Niazi</name></author><summary type="html">People often complain that they don’t have the time to practise mindfulness. If your one of those busy ones, you might like this: Think about three things you do each day. Like brushing your teeth, being in nature and having lunch. Then link this activity to a mindfulness practice:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/wellpro-blog/uploads/2017/02/23/bbcollage1-4.jpg" /></entry></feed>